siemens-stiftung.org 2019-09-14

# Privacy policy - Siemens Stiftung

In this Privacy Policy, we will inform you about the type of information that Siemens Stiftung collects about you and the way that this information is used. Here you can also find out more about your rights as a data subject. Siemens Stiftung (hereinafter referred to as “we” or “us”) is responsible for the processing of data described in the following document. You will find more details in the **[imprint.](https://www.siemens-stiftung.org/footer/imprint/)**

## I. Processing of data on our websites

Here is an overview of the websites of operated by Siemens Stiftung:

As a fundamental principle, we do not identify visitors to our websites. When you visit our websites, we store the following information, which your browser transmits to our server:

  * Your abbreviated IP address

  * The date and time you accessed the sites

  * The name and address of the file called up
  * The amount of data transferred
  * Messages on whether the websites were successfully called up
  * Data identifying the browser and operating system you use

This data is processed to enable use of the website from a technical perspective (establishment of a connection). The data is also analyzed statistically in anonymized and aggregated form (i.e., in a way that does not permit identification of individual users) to ensure system security, facilitate technical administration of the network infrastructure and help us optimize our online content. The legal basis for this is section 6 (1) point (f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

### 2\. Processing of personal data

In addition, we process personal data on our websites only if you disclose it to us, such as by filling out a contact form, registering for a newsletter, applying for an empowering. people award, sending e-mail or registering for our media portal.

 **a) Contacting us (contact form, newsletter and job applications)**

If you disclose your personal data to us using contact forms, forms to register for newsletters, an application form for an award or e-mail, it will be used to reply to your inquiry or provide you with access to the services you requested (such as to supply you with information with our newsletter or to examine your application for a job). The legal basis for this is section 6 (1) point (a) or (b) of the GDPR. This data is not combined with usage data collected when you visit the websites (see section 1).

 **b)  Registration for our media portal**

The comments under a) also apply to personal data you disclose to us when registering for the members’ only section of our media portal.

After registering, you may request the closure of your account at any time in accordance with the terms and conditions of use for the Siemens Stiftung media portal. Please send your name, address and e-mail address to us at: [**medienportal@siemens-stiftung.org**](mailto:medienportal@siemens-stiftung.org). We will delete your registration and all data associated with your account except where we are legally required to retain it; such retention may be required by tax law, for example. After deletion, you will no longer be able to access the members’ only section of the media portal

If you visit one of our websites, we may store information on your computer in the form of cookies, which will allow us to automatically recognize your computer when you visit us the next time. Cookies enable us to adapt website content to your interests, for example, or to save your password so that you do not need to enter it every time. If you do not wish us to recognize your computer, please set your Internet browser to delete cookies from your hard drive, block all cookies or warn you before saving a cookie.

### 4\. Data processing by third-party providers – Google Analytics and Twitter

**a) We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”) for our websites**

Google Analytics enables us to analyze your use of our websites with the aid of a cookie. The information is transferred to a Google server in the United States and stored there in accordance with Google’s Privacy Policy. Google’s self-certification under the [**Privacy Shield**](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) offers an adequate level of protection for data stored in the United States.

In light of the current discussion about the use of analysis tools with full IP addresses, we would like to point out that we use Google Analytics with the “_anonymizeIp()” extension. This shortens IP addresses to prevent any direct association with specific persons.

You can prevent the storage of cookies by activating the respective setting in your browser software. A further way of preventing web usage data (including your abbreviated IP address) generated by the cookie from being transmitted to [**Google** ](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)and processed there is to download and install the browser plugin found here:

Finally, you can also block Google Analytics from saving your data by clicking on the link “Deactivate Google Analytics” on the website in question. An opt-out cookie will prevent the future collection of your data when you visit this website.

×

## Google Analytics

Google Analytics has been deactivated for the current session.

**b) Our webpages utilize features of the Twitter service**

Our webpages utilize features of the Twitter service. This social plugin is considered standard in the modern media landscape and therefore important for distributing our content. These features are provided by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA.

Your data is protected due to the fact that there is no direct integration of content from Twitter. Personally-identifying data is not automatically shared with third-parties. To protect your privacy, we explicitly inform you prior to displaying third-party content or prior to transferring data to Twitter. Users can consent to the transfer of data and the display of such content with the so-called two-click solution.

The legal basis for processing user data following successful user consent is Art. 6 Para. 1 page 1 lit. a GDPR. If a user consents to third-party content, this preference will be saved in the user’s internet browser. With the Tweet plugin, we integrate content from our own Twitter presences. We do not receive any information about the contents of any transmitted data or its use from Twitter. Additional information can be found in Twitter’s data protection notice ** [Twitter.  ](https://twitter.com/de/privacy)**This consent can be revoked at any time.

×

## Twitter

Twitter has been deactivated for the current session.

## II. Processing of data in our contact database

### 1\. Purpose and legal basis of the processing 

Our contact database is used to maintain a current list of institutions and contact partners who are important to Siemens Stiftung’s activities. The database contains the contact information of individuals who have a connection to the work carried out by Siemens Stiftung or a professional interest in the activities or a particular focal point of Siemens Stiftung.

We use the contact database to carry out the mission defined in the foundation’s charter, particularly those aspects related to the fostering of secure basic services, high-quality education and cultural understanding  (you will find the detailed catalogue of the foundation’s missions in section 2 (1) of our charter).

We use your contact for such purposes as:

  * Contacting you in connection with specific questions,

  * Inviting you to events that are relevant to you or

  * Informing you about upcoming or ongoing projects that are relevant to you.

The legal basis of the processing of your data in our contact database is section 6 (1) point (f) of the GDPR (legitimate interest).

### 2\. Categories of personal data that are processed

To fulfill the purposes listed in section II (1), we process personal master data (in particular, your second name and first name) and contact data (in particular, your (office) address, e-mail address, telephone number and contact options in social networks).

## III. Transmission of data

We cooperate with service providers who help us deliver our offering. These service providers process data solely on behalf of and under the control of Siemens Stiftung and only for the purposes specified in this privacy policy.

If use of these service providers results in data being transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, Siemens Stiftung ensures an appropriate level of data protection by means of contractual arrangements (termed “standard data protection clauses”) or other mechanisms authorized by the GDPR. The particular clauses involved can be found online at **[Link](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/?uri=CELEX:02010D0087-20161217). **

We store personal data only for as long as it is required to provide you with the services you requested, to protect legitimate interest or to comply with statutory retention periods.

Data that is collected while you surf on our websites (see section I (1)) and that may constitute personal data under the law is stored for a period of 14 days, unless an exceptional incident (such as after an attack by hackers) requires it to be stored for a longer period of time.

Data without reference to specific persons can be stored permanently.

## V. Your rights and points of contact

Under the GDPR, you are entitled to the following rights:

 **a) **General rights****

You may demand access to and information on data stored concerning you, and you have the right to receive, in a commonly used and machine-readable format, the data you have provided. You may also demand that your data be erased or rectified and processing of it restricted in cases where you have legitimate grounds. If your personal data is transferred to a country outside the EEA that does not offer an adequate level of protection, you may request a copy of the agreement that ensures an adequate level of protection of personal data.

 ** **b) Withdrawal of your consent****

If you have consented to your personal data being processed on the website, you may withdraw that consent at any time with future effect.

 **c) **Right to object****

 **You have the right to object to use of your personal data if we use it based on a weighing of interests (section  6 (1) point (f) of the GDPR). In that case, we will no longer use your data, unless we have an overriding interest in doing so. You may object to use of your data for communication purposes, such as to send you mailing campaigns, at any time without any further weighing of interests.**

 **d) **Points of contact****

If you wish to exercise the above rights, you may contact Siemens Stiftung or our Data Protection Officer, Karin Hagen ([karin.hagen@siemens-stiftung.](mailto:karin.hagen@siemens-stiftung.)org). directly in writing or by e-mail. You may also directly contact the responsible data protection authority if you have questions or wish to lodge a complaint. The authority responsible for Siemens Stiftung is the Bavarian Data Protection Authority (BayLDA).
